hello.com 2003-12-12

# Picasa: Automated Digital Photo Organizer software, instant photo albums, sharing & printing: Privacy Policy

|  |  |  |  |  |  |   

Picasa, Inc. Privacy Policy

**Picasa, Inc. ("Picasa")** is committed to protecting online user privacy. In order to ensure your privacy, information **Picasa** collects is used only in the manner and for the purposes described below. 

This "Privacy Policy" discloses the privacy practices governing **Picasa** 's knowing collection, use, and disclosure of information. Capitalized terms shall have the meaning designated in **Picasa's Terms and Conditions** unless specifically defined in this Privacy Policy. 

Picasa Products and Services

Picasa Automatic Photo Organizing Software

**Picasa** 's proprietary technology presents you with a simple interface that helps you organize your digital pictures around the way you think -- visually, spatially, around memories and feelings. **Picasa** allows the user to manage their digital pictures effortlessly. It even lets you print them professionally! You may find more information about our **Picasa** photo organizing software by [clicking here](). 

Hello from Picasa

'Hello' from **Picasa** is a new way to connect people sharing their photos and web pages, where friends and family communicate with words and pictures faster than email and with more privacy than the internet-or even other chat clients. Hello combines the best of picture sharing and instant messaging so anyone can trade single images or entire slide shows not only securely, but immediately. You may find more information about 'Hello' by [clicking here](http://www.hello.com/). 

Picasa Web Sites  
User Consent to Privacy Policy

Any person accessing, browsing, or otherwise using **Picasa** 's web sites ("Site"), either manually or via an automated device or program, shall be considered a "Visitor." Further, a Visitor that registers at the Site, downloads, orders prints and/or makes purchases of products shall be considered a "User." All Visitors are bound by the terms of this Privacy Policy. Visitors consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of Visitor information pursuant to the terms of this Privacy Policy. 

Information Collected

**Picasa** collects every User's name, billing and/or shipping address, email address, credit card information with related expiration date ("Personally Identifiable Information"). **Picasa** stores all Personally Identifiable Information except a User's credit card information, in which case only the last four digits and the related expiration date is stored. **Picasa** does not collect any Personally Identifiable Information from Visitors that are not Users. 

**Picasa** collects and stores Visitors' site referral information, browsing patterns, technical information (e.g., the Visitor's browser version, IP address, and operating system), and other Site use information through the use of "Cookies" ("Information"). (For more information regarding Cookies, see below.) **Picasa** associates the Information obtained about a User to the User's Personally Identifiable Information. 

Use of Information and Personally Identifiable Information

**Picasa** uses Information and Personally Identifiable Information to better understand the use of the Site and to better tailor the Site to Visitor and User preferences, as well as for customer support purposes. **Picasa** also may use the name, street address and email address that Users supply to contact Users, as well as to send Users promotional or other materials. To unsubscribe from our mailing list, please follow the directions set forth within the promotional or other materials you receive from us or email [unsubscribe@picasa.net](mailto:unsubscribe@picasa.net). 

Disclosure of Information and Personally Identifiable Information to Third Parties

**Picasa** may disclose Information to third parties who assist us in providing the Software Products and the Services to you. For example, we may share your Information with our image processing partners in order to process your print orders. We may engage third parties to make improvements on our site, to offer new products and to allow us to customize your experience on the Site and with the Software Products and the Services. 

**Picasa** does not otherwise disclose Information or Personally Identifiable Information to third parties, except when required to do so by law pursuant to a search warrant, subpoena, or other legal process. 

Cookies

**Picasa** uses a feature of Internet Web browsers called a "Cookie", which is a file that a Visitor's Web browser places on a Visitor's computer's hard drive, to assign an identification code to the computer and to collect and store Information. 

**Picasa** associates the Information obtained about a User to the User's Personally Identifiable Information. We do not and cannot use Cookies to retrieve individual Personally Identifiable Information about Visitors from a Visitor's computer unless the Visitor knowingly and willingly provided such information. Cookies do not contain any credit card information. 

Linked Internet Web Sites

The Site provides hyperlinks, which are highlighted words or pictures within a hypertext document that, when clicked, take you to another place within the document or to another document altogether, to other web sites not controlled by **Picasa**. These hyperlinked web sites may contain privacy provisions that are different from those provided herein. **Picasa** is not responsible for the collection, use, or disclosure of information collected through these web sites, and **Picasa** expressly disclaims any and all liability related to such collection, use, or disclosure. 

Sharing Your Images

When you share your images with others through Hello by **Picasa** or by e-mail, recipients can then further share your images, modify, alter and/or print those images, if they choose. It is important that you ensure that your images are sent to the correct Hello network member and to the correct email addresses. 

Children

**Picasa** 's Sites are not directed towards children 13 years of age or under and **Picasa** does not knowingly collect any information from children 13 years of age or under through the Sites. 

Security

This Site has password security measures to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the Information and Personally Identifiable Information under our control. **Picasa** makes no representations or warranties with regard to the sufficiency of these security measures. **Picasa** shall not be responsible for any actual or consequential damages that result from a lapse in compliance with this Privacy Policy as a result of a security breach or technical malfunction. 

Sale of Assets

In the event that another company acquires **Picasa** or its assets, **Picasa** reserves the right to include Information and Personally Identifiable Information among the assets transferred to the acquiring company. 

Amendments to Privacy Policy

**Picasa** reserves the right to amend this Privacy Policy periodically. Use of Information and Personally Identifiable Information that **Picasa** gathers now is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time the Information or Personally Identifiable Information is used. Any amendments made to this Privacy Policy will be considered effective ten (10) days after the amendments are posted on the Site. 

Contact Information

If Visitors have any questions about our products, services or Privacy Policy or to correct your Registration Information, please contact **Picasa, Inc., Customer Support, 130 W. Union Street, Pasadena, CA 91103**. 

Visitors may also email [nfo@picasa.net](mailto:info@picasa.net) with questions about our Privacy Policy, our products and services, and [registration@picasa.net](mailto:registration@picasa.net) to correct your Registration Information. 

Revised: October 8, 2003

|  |  |  |  |  |   
---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---
